<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Handling of Image files in TAPAS Records</title>
            <author>
               <orgName>TAPAS Project</orgName>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Encoded by, </resp>
               <persName>Benjamin J. Doyle (modified by Mary Isbell)</persName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>
               <orgName>the TEI Archiving, Publishing, and Access Service (TAPAS)</orgName>
            </publisher>
            <address>
               <addrLine>360 Huntington Avenue</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Northeastern University</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Boston, MA 02115</addrLine>
            </address>
            <date>2017-01-17</date>
            <availability>
               <p>This file is free to download, share, or repurpose for educational and project development purposes.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <p>Basic encoding, modeling handling of image files in TAPAS for TEI Records.</p>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc> </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-11-11" who="#BJD"> added header </change>
         <change when="2018-04-30" who="#MEI">incorporated links to images uploaded to Flickr</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div>
            <head>BASIC ENCODING SCENARIOS</head>
            <p>TAPAS supports the display of image files in two ways:</p>
            <p>1.<![CDATA[<figure>]]></p>
            <p>Here is an image file, "TYI1064.jpg," which we've uploaded to Flickr and then encoded into our TEI file by including the file's path as
               the value (in quotation marks) for the attribute @url on <![CDATA[<graphic>]]>. Our image file is NOT loaded along with file as part of
               the TAPAS Record (because this doesn't work right now), so we are referencing the full url of the image at Flickr. To do this (to
               reference an image file that lives on another web server), we add the full url path on the @url value. To get the URL from Flickr,
               click the "Download" button on your image page (it looks like an arrow pointing down), Decide which size image you want (I've used
               "small" for this example) and Control-click/right-click on that size, Select "Copy link location", which will add the URL to your
               clipboard, and Paste the URL into your TEI.Here is what it should look like (see the XML view to see how this is encoded)</p>
            <figure>
               <graphic url="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/919/41668854741_a55947fd40_m_d.jpg"/>
            </figure>

            <p>2.<![CDATA[@facs on <pb/>]]></p>
            <p>We may also wish to add page images of our marked-up text. We could do this by uploading our page images as "Auxillary Files" for our
               TAPAS Record (but this isn't working at the moment). Instead, we can call on these files following a similar approach as outlined
               above, except we add the file name and path as a value of @facs on <![CDATA[<pb/>]]>:</p>
            <p>Pretend this is the last line of a page in my document <pb n="1"
                  facs="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/919/41668854741_a55947fd40_m_d.jpg"/> and this is where that line continues on the next
               page.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head rend="bold">IMAGES IN NOTES</head>
            <p>You can add images into your notes by using same setup as scenario 1 in Basic Encoding above. To see how this works, click the note at
               the end of this sentence.<note>Here's an image contained within a note: <figure>
                     <graphic url="https://farm1.staticflickr.com/919/41668854741_a55947fd40_m_d.jpg"/>
                  </figure>
               </note></p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
